<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>DIY on Bogdan Penkovsky, PhD</title>
    <link>https://penkovsky.com/tags/diy/</link>
    <description>Recent content in DIY on Bogdan Penkovsky, PhD</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; Bogdan Penkovsky 2024</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 17 Feb 2022 00:10:00 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://penkovsky.com/tags/diy/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>A Quadcopter From Scratch: FPV Upgrade</title>
      <link>https://penkovsky.com/post/fpv-quad/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Feb 2022 00:10:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://penkovsky.com/post/fpv-quad/</guid>
      <description>It has been a while since I was thinking about upgrading my drone to a first person view version aka FPV. The idea was placing a camera for video streaming in real time. My first attempt was with a small raspi board and streaming image data from a raspi camera via WiFi. Because of the latency, range, and complicated setup this solution was not very practical.
Therefore, I decided to make a &amp;quot;real&amp;quot; FPV drone.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Quadcopter From Scratch</title>
      <link>https://penkovsky.com/post/quad/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 May 2021 11:33:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://penkovsky.com/post/quad/</guid>
      <description>Recently NASA has made the first powered flight on Mars. They have deployed a drone called Ingenuity costing about $85 million. The helicopter was able to fly on about ten meters altitude (as of May, 7) over the surface of the Red Planet.
Coincidently, I have also built a flying drone. This looked like a good challenge and an opportunity to learn about unmanned aerial vehicles (UAVs).
Here is what I learned.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>3D Printing Tutorial: Designing a Micro Drone Frame</title>
      <link>https://penkovsky.com/post/beatle/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Mar 2021 18:40:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://penkovsky.com/post/beatle/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Here is a step by step tutorial on how to design objects for 3D printing using
OpenSCAD. We illustrate the design process by creating a micro quadcopter
frame. This small drone bears the code name of Beatle-1.  After following the
tutorial you will be able to conceive your own designs for 3D printing.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Making Your Self-Driving Robot</title>
      <link>https://penkovsky.com/post/self-driving-robot/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Nov 2020 23:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://penkovsky.com/post/self-driving-robot/</guid>
      <description>We will build an autonomous robot. Captured by robot&#39;s camera, video stream will be analyzed by a neural network. The network will be running on the onboard Raspberry Pi that will steer the robot. Before you start with the project, I want you to answer two questions. First, how everything will be attached mechanically? Second, what will be the energy source? While your autonomous robot can work from a cardboard box, having a mechanically sound chassis will greatly improve the result on the AI training stage.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Connecting To Raspberry Pi Over WiFi</title>
      <link>https://penkovsky.com/post/raspi-ssh-over-wifi/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Apr 2020 16:03:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://penkovsky.com/post/raspi-ssh-over-wifi/</guid>
      <description>Raspberry Pi is great. It is a small and cheap computer that can be used for a variety of projects. Sometimes you may wish to remotely control a Rasperry Pi that is in your local WiFi network. This is possible and even quite easy.
We will use a Secure Shell aka SSH to establish a remote connection. I assume that you have previously connected your Raspberry Pi board to a WiFi network.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>